There must be someother explanation.
一定有其他解释
I have an idea - shallwe go for a walk?
我有个主意－咱们去散步好吗?
When there's marriage without love,there'll be love without marriage.
当婚姻没有爱时会有无婚姻的爱
But Robert and I marriedfor love...
但Robert和我是因爱而结合的...
Of course. And so did I.
当然，我也曾是的
But before the year was over...
但当热情逝去后...
Benito was lifting all kindsof petticoats.
Benito开始摆弄各式衬裙
I had to dismiss my best maid.
我不得已辞去了最好的女佣
No, no, I remember.
不，我想起来了
I passed her on tomy cousin.
我把她送给了我的表亲
Her husband was soshort-sighted, I thought.
她丈夫很短视，我觉得
But he navigated by scent,it seems.
他好像是循着气味查的
So unfortunate.
真不幸
Believe me, darling,it happens to us all.
相信我，这我们都经历过
Undying love is like theghost in your villa.
不死的爱就象你别墅里的鬼魂
Everybody talks about it...
人们都谈论...
but try and find one personwho has seen it.
但试试去找一个得到的人吧
- Can I ask you a favour?- Anything at all.
- 你能帮我个忙吗?- 任何事
About, Mrs Erlynne...
关于Erlynne太太...
Very clever woman.
很聪明的女人
She threw me out last night.
她昨晚把我扔出来了
Knows what a fool I am.Knows it as well as I do myself.
知道了我有多蠢知道的跟我自己一样清楚
She's meeting me herefor tea, though.
她会在这跟我碰面喝茶
It's a great thing to come across awoman who thoroughly understands me.
能跟一个完全理解我的女人走到一起真是太棒了
Would you mind not bringingher to our party tonight?
今晚别带她到我们的舞会你会介意吗?
That's the favour?
这是你要的帮忙吗?
Meg feels it might makethings awkward.
Meg 觉得那样会使事情变的不舒服
So it's true, then?
那么是真的喽?
I don't believe it.You don't seem the type.
我不相信，你不是那个类型
Though I will say Mrs Erlynne's damnfascinating. Hard to resist, but...
尽管我会说Erlynne太太实在迷人难以抗拒，但是……
You're not serious, are you?
你不是认真的，对吧?
I warn you, you'll have tofight me for her.
我警告你，你得跟我决斗才能抢她
And I'm a man in love.
而我可是个坠入爱河的男人
What are you talking about?
你说什么呢?
This ways, Mrs Erlynne.
这边请，Erlynne太太
- Thanks.- You're welcome.
- 多谢- 不客气
- Come with me.- Where are you taking me?
- 跟我来- 你往哪里带我?
- Let go of my arm.- I have to talk to you.
- 放开我的手- 我非跟你谈谈不可
I'm meeting Lord Augustos.
我要见Augustos大人
You must leave Amalfi at once.
你马上得离开Amalfi
And go where? You've paid myrent here for the season.
去哪?你已经替我付了一个季的租金
I'll pay it somewhere else. I wantyou on the first plane out tomorrow.
我会付其他地方的帐我要你上明天第一班飞机
- I don't understand.- People are talking.
- 我不理解- 人们在谈论
About us.
我们
I don't see the humour.
我不觉得可笑
Bury a real secret anda false one pops up in its place?
在这里，埋葬一个秘密会冒出另一个假的吗？
There's a certain irony,you have to admit.
你得承认确实这么荒谬
I'm not ready to leave.I'm enjoying myself here.
我不想走，在这挺高兴的
I'm begging you.
我恳求你
Think of Meg. If she knew thatyou were her mother...
想想Meg，如果她知道你是她妈妈...
it would destroy her.
那会毁灭她的
Meg, of the magnificentWindemeres?
Meg, 高尚的Windemeres?
Family scandal is unhealthyfor aspiring politicians.
家族丑闻对一个有抱负的政治家是不健康的
I'm not the only pragmatistin this room.
我不是这屋里唯一一个爱管闲事的人
Pragmatist? Twenty years,and not a word.
爱管闲事? 20年，音讯全无
You turn up when she marriesa man with money.
当她嫁入豪门时你倒出现了
You call that pragmatism?I can think of other words.
你管那叫爱管闲事？我有更好的形容方法
Are you trying to hurtmy feelings?
你想伤害我的感情吗?
Do you have any? That can'tbe purchased, I mean.
你有感情吗？那是不能买卖的
How much - to get youon the first flight out?
多少钱，能让你坐上头班机走开?
I feel every time he'skissed me it's filthy.
我觉得每次他吻我都是不洁的
A lie, every minute we'vebeen together.
我们在一起的每分钟都是谎言
How could he?
他怎么能呢?
Every man is born truthfuland every man dies a liar.
每个男人生来都说实话但死时都是骗子
Now, whatever you do, youmustn't make a scene.
现在，无论你做什么都不能引人注目
It's too unpleasant.And you waste your energy.
太令人不快而且也浪费你的精力
No, of course not. I wouldn't.
当然不会
Crying is the refugeof plain women.
哭是平庸女人的庇护所
Pretty women go shopping.
漂亮女人去购物
Be on that plane.I'll send the cash.
上那班飞机我会把现金奉上
Did I hear you correctly?
我没听错吧?
That Meg Windemere isyour daughter?
Meg Windemere 是你的女儿?
My daughter?
我女儿?
Robert's wife?
Robert的妻子?
How dare you.
你怎么敢
She must be twenty at least.Her mother?
她至少有20岁了，她的妈妈?
Do I look as old as all that?
我真的看上去有那么老吗?
Of course not.
当然不是
I must have nodded off.
我一定是在打盹
You were dozing.Go back to sleep.
你困了，回去接着睡吧
Come on.
快点
No business tonight.We can talk another day.
今晚不谈生意，我们改天再谈
- Good to see you.- Lovely party.
-高兴见到你-晚会真好
More champagne.
再来点香槟
Welcome.Have a great party.
欢迎，好好玩
- Good evening, Mr Dumby.- Oh, good evening, Mrs Stutfield.
- 晚上好，Dumby先生- 哦，晚上好，Stutfield太太
Last party of the season,I suppose.
这一季最后的晚会了吧
- It's been delightful, hasn't it?- Quite delightful.
- 真令人愉快，是吧?- 非常令人愉快
Good evening. Here it is,the last party of the season.
晚上好，这里，是本季最后的晚会了
I suppose so. It's been a very dullseason, though, hasn't it?
我猜也是，尽管是个闷人的季节是吧？
Dull. Yes, terribly dull.
闷人，是啊，很闷
- Evening, Cecil.- Hello, Dumby.
－晚安, Cecil- 你好, Dumby
I suppose this'll be the lastparty of the season.
我希望这是本季最后的晚会了
Surely not. Probablybe two more at least.
肯定不是，至少还会有两个
I had the oddest dream today.
我今天做了个怪透了的梦
A bit of it has justcome back to me...
刚刚想起了一小部分...
So what are we drinking?
我们喝什么呢?
- Where's the birthday girl?- Transforming herself.
- 生日女郎在哪里?- 正在变形
Sausages and women.
香肠和女人
If you want to enjoy theexperience...
如果你想享受她们...
never watch thepreparation of either.
千万别看过程
- Is that new?- Just out of the box. Do you like it?
- 那是新的吗?- 刚出盒，你喜欢吗?
You might be a little cold.I'll get you a wrap.
你会有点冷，我给你拿个披肩吧
And spoil the lines? Didn't your friendteach you about Italian fashion?
毁掉线条吗，你朋友没教你意大利时装吗?
My friend?
我朋友?
I saw the cheques. Don't even...
我看见支票了，少来...
Lady Plymdale, so good ofyou to come.
Plymdale女士, 你来真好
Do you want another glass ofchampagne?
再要一杯香槟吗?
Let's get us both some.
我俩都来点吧
Why don't you ask me how I am?
你怎么给我问安?
I like people to ask.
我喜欢人给我问安
It shows a widespreadinterest in my health.
表示对我健康的普遍关心
And you can't imagine howcomforting that is.
你不会知道那让人多舒服
Lovely party.
晚会不错
- How are you, Cecil?- Oh, not well at all.
- 你好, Cecil?- 一点都不好
I'd like Alessandra...
我希望Alessandra...
to know Mr. Hopperfrom Australia.
认识一下从澳洲来的Hopper先生
- Would you introduce her?- Would you just excuse me for a moment?
- 你可以介绍一下吗?- 请容我一点时间好吗?
Go with Mr Windemere.Thank you.
跟Windemere先生走谢谢
She's my last, you know.I will miss her.
她是我最小的，我会想她的
But it's best to get them outof the nest...
但是在她们开始攻击你之前...
before they turn on you.
还是把她们从巢里赶走吧
Girls begin by loving their mothers.But as they grow they judge us.
女孩最初是爱妈妈的但长大后就会评价你
Rarely do they forgive us.
很少会宽容
Oh, poor fool.He'll never learn.
哦，可怜的傻子就是学不会
Which fool?Don't make me choose.
那个傻子？别让我选
Tuppy,he's brought Mrs Erlynne.
Tuppy,他把Erlynne太太带来了
All the women will snub her.
所有女人都会怠慢她
She may have betterluck with the men.
她跟男人在一起没准会有点运气
It is because of men...
那是因为男人...
that women distrust other women.
女人才不信任女人
Women don't trust women,men don't trust women...
女人不信女人,男人也不信女人...
no-one trusts women.
没人相信女人
It's what binds the Hinduand the Catholic.
就是这个联合了印度教和天主教
I know I promised, but I must tellyou how beautiful you look tonight.
我知道我发过誓但我必需说你今晚真美
Well, if you must, you must.
好吧，如果你非说就说吧
I beg your pardon, I waslooking for someone else.
请原谅，我在找其他人
Well, you found me.
而你找到了我
Mrs Erlynne.
Erlynne太太
May I call you Stella?
我可以叫你Stella吗？
Lord Augustus is gettingme champagne.
Augustus大人给我拿香槟去了
You and I can trade favours.
你和我可以交换恩宠
Tempting, but no.
很诱人，但算了
I'd rather he didn't see us under themoonlight. He might misunderstand.
我宁愿他不会看到月光下的我们或许会令他误解
Hear me out.
听我说
Windemere's fortune exceeds Tuppy's.
Windemere财富胜过Tuppy
Why change horses now?
干嘛现在换马?
You can have waht youwant and Meg's free.
你得到所要的，Meg也自由了
Free?
自由?
She hasn't the courage to leave him.
她没有离开他的勇气
But if it's clear to her thathe's with you...
但如果明确了他跟你在一起...
He's not.
他没有
You've been buying idle gossip.You should get a refund.
你买的谣言不可靠，赶紧去退款吧
Excuse me.
请原谅
I had to invite her, Dumby.
我非邀请她不可, Dumby
The point is, she's a changed woman.You can see it in her eyes.
问题是，她变了你可以从她眼睛里看出来
Do you think she'd look atyou if you were poor?
你以为你要是穷她会看你一眼吗?
Do you think I'd look at herif she were ugly?
那你以为如果她丑我会看她吗?
Fair's fair, exchange ratesand so forth.
公平是公平，互利互惠
I know she's had her thisand her that, but...
我知道她有点这有点那...
if a man can toleratehis own past...
但如果男人能有过去...
Why not a past in his wife?At any rate...
他妻子干嘛不能有?而且肯出钱...
it's wipe the slate.Clean start.
什么都能擦干净重新开始
She and I, we...understand each other.
她和我……我们可以互相理解
And you know what they say.
你知道他们怎么说
Every saint has past,every sinner has a future.
每个圣人都有个过去而每个罪人都有个未来
I'm going to ask her to marryme if she'll have me.
如果她肯要，我想向她求婚
You know why they call itan altar, Tuppy?
你知道人们为什么称之为圣坛, Tuppy?
It's where they makehuman sacrifices.
因为那里以人为祭祀
I had a dream aboutMrs Erlynne today.
我今天梦到 Erlynne太太
Yes, well...
是吗...
you couldn't help it,I suppose. She...
你是情不自禁吧...
she is quite the woman.
她真了不起
But in future...
但以后……
please try to dream ofsomeone else.
还是请梦别人去吧
Don't you think you'vehad enough?
你不觉得自己喝够了吗?
- Lovely party.- Thanks for coming.
- 晚会很好- 谢谢赏光
Meg?
I have to change.
我得去换衣服
- Did you see her?- Don't.
- 你看见她了吗?- 没有
You're lovely.
你很可爱
It's ridiculous on a woman at her age.
她那岁数的女人穿真荒唐
Why didn't you tell me?
你干嘛不告诉我?
You said you were my friend.
你说过你是我的朋友
Men and women can't be friends.
男女之间无法成朋友
- Meg?- No.
- Meg?- 不
Can you stay with him?
你能跟他在一起吗?
Can you get into bedwith him tonight?
你今晚能跟他上床吗?
Tomorrow night?Nights after that?
明晚?以后呢？
You said yourself, there's noforgiving a man who betrays his wife.
你自己说的，男人背叛妻子不可原谅
What will you choose?
你怎么选?
A false degrading marriage, or yourown true self, free of compromise?
一个虚伪可耻的婚姻还是一个没有妥协的真我？
I've loved you from the beginning.It's the truth.
我对你一见钟情，这是真的
Moment you held out your hand to me inthe glove shop, I thought 'there she is".
你在手套店抽出手来的那刻我想“就是她了”
And then, suppose I'd walkedby without stopping?
那时，我是否该不加停留的离去呢?
Just the thought of it.
只那样一想
I've never loved anyone until now.
至今我从未爱过
Stop.
停
John?
I'm sorry, I didn't meanto startle you.
对不起，我不想吓你
I'm looking for Meg. If you see her,it's important.
我在找Meg，你看见她了吗？
Have you had a row?
你排队了吗?
A little misunderstanding.
一个小舞会
Try the bar.
看看酒吧
Tuppy's given up smokes for her.
Tuppy为她戒烟了
Women.
女人
Women inspire us to great things.
Women 给我们向上的灵感
Then somehow prevent usfrom doing any of them.
却又不明所以地阻止我们实施
He's proposing to her.
他向她求婚了
It will be his third time up the aisle.
该是他第三次上圣坛了
Hope trumps experience, Dumby.
希望是个制胜之举， Dumby
It's God's joke on the human race.
是人类竞争中上帝之玩笑而已
He's quite convinced she'schanged her spots.
他确信她已改过自新了
Care to make it interesting?
想把那变有趣吗?
I told you I was serious.
告诉你我是认真的了
Hasn't anyone warned youagainst me?
没有人警告你该反对我吗?
Oh, yes. Everyone.
哦，是的，所有人
Put it away.
把它拿开
Now, you don't have to loveme right away.
你并不用马上就爱上我
Think of the money.
想想钱
Suppose I marry you, and in a yearyour investments go sour.
假设我跟你结婚一年内你的投资缩水了
I'll be stuck with a pauper.
我就被个叫花子栓住了
On the other hand...
另一个情形是...
I could drop dead on the golf coursenext Tuesday...
我可能下礼拜二死在高尔夫球场……
and you'd be left verywell-appointed.
而你可就富裕了
Life's a gamble, Stella.
生命就是赌博, Stella
I don't know what to say.
我不知如何作答
People say too much as it is.
人讲太多话
Mrs Windemere andMrs Erlynne...
Windemere太太跟Erlynne太太...
Iook like mother and daughter,don't they?
看起来就跟母女是的，是吧?
They're wearing the same dress.
他们穿着同样的衣服
Well, that'll be it.
就是的
Come away with me.
跟我走吧
We could set sail tonight.
我们今晚就出海
Please.
求你
Is this your idea of a joke?
这是你开玩笑的方式吗？
I need to speak to you.It's about Darlington.
我得跟你谈谈Darlington
Follow me.
跟我来
He's in love with Meg.
他爱上Meg了
I know we said cash, so I'm raisingthe amount. I want you to leave now.
我知道我说到钱的问题，我要提高数目让你现在就走
I'd be more concernedif I were you.
我要是你会更小心的
You're not me.
你不是我
The problem is I've beenlying to my wife...
问题是我对我妻子说谎了...
and I'm not very good at it.
而我很不在行
I can add up the rumours...
我可以再添加谣言...
and show her a big fat zero.I'm Tuppy's girl.
让她看什么都没有我是Tuppy的女人
- Case closed.- I'll do my own explaining, get out.
- 案件结束了- 我自己会解释，你出去吧
I'd like to say goodbye to her.
我要跟她道别
You said goodbye to her twentyyears ago. No second chances.
你20年前就跟她道别了没有选择余地
I'll leave first.
我先离开
- We shouldn't walk out together.- You're the expert.
- 我们不该一起出去- 你是专家
Count to a 100.
数100下
Mrs Windemere?
Windemere太太?
Dear Robert, I thought ourmarriage was perfect.
亲爱的Robert, 我以为我们的婚姻是完美的
I thought we wouldalways be together.
我以为我们永远会在一起
If you love Mrs Erlynne,you should be with her.
如果你爱Erlynne太太,你该跟他在一起
I feel so foolish.
我觉得真愚蠢
Everyone knew but me.
每个人都知道，只有我不知道
Meg, let me in,I wanna talk to you.
Meg, 让我进去我要跟你谈谈
Please, open the door.
请开门
There is nothing between meand Stella Erlynne.
我和Stella Erlynne之间什么都没有
How can you think it?
你怎么能那么想?
She's old for God's sake.She dyes her hair.
上帝她那么老，还染头发
She paints her facelike an Indian.
她象印度人一样粉刷她的脸
She's a cold,selfish woman.
她是个冷血自私的女人
Not all attractiveonce you know her.
如果你认识她就知道她根本不吸引人
Look, she was goingto damage someone.
她想毁灭一个人
A person who'd never doneher any harm.
一个不会伤害她的人
She came here with a secret thatwould have broken your heart.
她带来的秘密会伤你的心
Look, I wanted to tell you. I justdidn't know how.
我想告诉你，但不知如何做
I was trying to protect you,you have to believe me.
我是想保护你，你得相信我
She asked me for moneyand I gave it to her, but...
她管我要钱，我给了她...
I'm not proud ofbeing blackmailed...
我并不以被勒索而自豪...
I didn't know what else to do.
我不知所措
I should have told youat the start.
我该开始就告诉你的
I'm not lying to you now, I...
我不打算再骗你了...
I love you.
我爱你
And there's no otherwoman in my heart...
我心里没有别人...
or in my bed.
床上也没有
Meg...
please open the door.
请开门
We both had toomuch champagne.
我俩都喝太多香槟了
We can talk in the morning.
我们明早再谈吧
- Splendid.- Thank you for coming.
- 太棒了- 谢谢你来
- Lovely party. Goodnight, Robert.- I'll see you at the club.
- 晚会不错， Robert.- 我们在俱乐部见
- There's the girl.- Take Windemere to the club.
- 女孩在这里啊-带Windemere去俱乐部
Keep him out all night.Get him drunk if you have to.
整晚守着他，如果能就灌醉他
- Just don't let him come home.- Why?
- 就是别让他回家- 为什么?
What? What?
什么啊？
I like you, I do.
我喜欢你，真的
But if this is going to workbetween us, you can't do that.
但是如果想奏效的话，你就不能那样
- Do what?- "Where? What? Why?"
- 哪样？- “哪里？什么？为什么”
I can't always explainmyself to myself...
我不能老解释跟...
let alone anyone else.
别人解释自己
Good for you -takes the pressure off.
不错，放开压力
Nine times out of ten, mendon't give two pins about why...
9成的男人...
they just feel obligedto take an interest.
无法接受被强加的兴趣
So, I'll do exactly as you wish...
那么我就按吩咐行事...
and I'll feel as ifwe're married already.
假装感觉我们已经结婚了
Oh, can you get yourselfhome all right?
哦，你能安全回家吗?
Why, Tuppy...
哇, Tuppy...
you're the first man who'sasked me that.
你是第一个这么问我的男人
I don't need to be the first,Stella. Just the last.
我不必是第一个Stella，就当最后一个吧
There's a taxi waitingat the end of the dock.
在码头上有辆出租车等着
My husband sent you.
我丈夫让你来的
Your husband thinks you'rein bed sleeping off...
你丈夫以为你喝了一瓶矿泉水...
a litre of Perrier Jouet.
已经睡了
Let's go.
走吧
He gave me money,that's all.
他给我钱了，就这样
I'm an old friend of the family.
我是家族的老朋友
Do you think I'm stupid?
你以为我傻吗?
Married to man you loveand running off...
嫁给了一个爱的人，又跟...
with an international playboy?Do I think you're stupid?
一个国际花花公子离家?我以为你傻?
This is none of your business.
这跟你无关
You think because hems are higherand women can vote...
你以为开衩变高了，我们可以投票...
that anything hasreally changed for us?
一切就会为我们而改变吗?
Friends will stop calling.
朋友们会不跟你联系
He'll be invited into homesyou're not.
他会受邀回家，而你不会
You manage.
你可以做到
Don't compare yourself.
别吓比较
It takes practice andskill to live without regret.
无悔的生活需要准备和练习
A marriage takesyour whole heart.
一段婚姻需要你整个心灵
Selfish people can't pull it off,but you're not that.
自私的人做不到，但你不是
You can succeed wherethe rest of us fail.
我们都失败了你也不会
- Why should I believe you?- Don't believe me, believe him.
- 我干嘛要信你?- 别信我，信他
He's been faithful to you,I'll swear it on my life.
他对你是忠诚的，我以性命担保
He told you to lie.
他让你撒谎
He doesn't evenknow you're here.
他甚至不知道你在这
He never has to know.
他不必知道
You want me to lie again?
你让我再撒谎吗?
Everything's spoiledbetween us. I can't.
我们间的一切都完了，我不能
What's happened to you?
你怎么了?
Who taught you to be sounforgiving?
谁教你这么不能宽容?
You made a mistake,don't make it worse.
你犯了个错，别再犯了
You shut your eyes to everythingthat isn't perfect...
你对不完美的东西熟视无睹...
you're just asking to fallinto a hole.
你被带向一个陷阱
Fine.
好吧
Go ahead.
去吧
Step over love to pick uppride and guilt.
放弃爱而选择傲慢和内疚吧
What will that tradebe worth in a year?
真是20岁这一年里
In twenty?
最赔了买卖了
Darlington, does your boatreally have to be so big?
Darlington, 你的船非得这么大吗?
You know what they say aboutmen with big boats.
你知道人们怎么议论有大船的男人吗？
- I should be getting home.- You'll take a cigar, surely?
- 我得回家了- 你得抽支雪茄，真的?
I thought you'd quitfor the love of a good woman.
我以为你放弃对好女人的爱了呢
Good woman isn't exactly themoniker I'd choose for Mrs Erlynne.
好女人可不是 Erlynne太太的名字
You imply she'sthe devil's handmaiden.
你在暗示她是魔鬼的侍女吗？
Dumby and I are just concernedfor your future.
Dumby和我正为你的未来担忧呢
Devilish women are a bother,and good ones are a bore.
魔鬼般的女人是麻烦好女人又太闷了
That's the only difference.
那是唯一的不同
Mrs Erlynne is neither a bothernor a bore.
Erlynne太太即不是麻烦也不是沉闷
You change your habits,but I doubt she'll change hers.
你改变了习惯但我怀疑她也会改变
I've bet Dumby fifty quid.
我跟 Dumby 赌了50块
Enough of this.
够了
I won't hear any more wordssaid against her.
我不想听反对她的话了
She's everything I've everwanted in a woman.
她是我对女人一切愿望的完美体现
My dear Tuppy, in this worldthere are only two tragedies.
我亲爱的Tuppy,这世界上只有两个惨剧
One is not getting what one wants,the other is getting it.
一是一无所获，一是得偿所愿
The last is very much the worst.The last is a real tragedy.
后者是最差的，真正的惨剧
Marriage.
婚姻
It has its pains - ask Edna.
痛苦万分，问Edna
Celibacy has no pleasures.
单身生活没乐趣
- What would you know about it?- I can learn.
- 你怎么知道?- 我可以学
If it will prove my love.
来证明我的爱
A woman who needs proof?
女人需要验证?
Before she'll leave her husband.
在她离开她丈夫以前
John, you are a cad.
John,你是个无赖
We're all in the gutter.
我们都在臭水沟里
But some of us are lookingat the stars.
而我们中的一些人却在看星星
What men call gallantry...
男人称它为“殷勤”
ans God's adultery...
上帝称它为“通奸”
is far more common where the climate's sultry.
这种事在天气闷热的地方，尤其容易发生
That's the one I bought Meg.
那是我买给Meg的
For her birthday.
生日礼物
Are you sure?
你肯定吗?
She must have left it last weekwhen you came for lunch.
必是上次你来吃饭时她落在这的
She was carrying it tonight.
可她今晚拿着来着
One fan looks very muchlike another.
扇子彼此相象
John?
- I've no idea.- Meg's not here, is she?
- 我不知道- Meg不是在这里吧?
No, of course not.
当然不是
- What's that?- I didn't hear anything.
- 那是什么?- 我什么都没听见
She's downstairs.
她在楼下
Calm down.You've had too much...
冷静你喝太多了...
Don't make an ass of yourself.
别让你自己出丑
Too late.
太晚了
- Bloody hell!- You better put some ice on that.
- 该死- 你弄点冰敷上吧
I thought it was mine.
我以为是我的呢
I must have picked upMrs Windemere's by mistake.
肯定是误拿了Windemere的
Tuppy, I swear, I had no idea.
Tuppy, 我发誓，我不知道
You owe Cecil fifty quid. Sorry.
你欠Cecil 50磅，对不起
It seems I'm the ass,Windemere. Not you.
好像是我出丑了Windemere，不是你
I spent the night on John's boat.
我在John船上过的夜
I had too much to drink.
我喝多了
Can I ask you to forgive me?
你能原谅我吗?
I did something very stupidlast night.
我昨夜做了很蠢的事
You're not in my league.
你不是我的同伙
I made a complete ass of myself.
我出了大丑
Ruined it for poor Tuppy.
毁了Tuppy
Better now than later, I guess.
但我想这迟早会发生
Tuppy?
His engagement toMrs Erlynne is off.
他取消了向Erlynne太太求婚
What are you talking about?
你说什么呢?
Last night on John's yacht, MrsErlynne was waiting in his bedroom.
昨晚在John游艇上，Erlynne在他卧室里等他
Look, I was drunk, I thought...
看，我喝多了，我以为...
I saw your fan, I thought that...
我看见了你的扇子，我以为...
I didn't think.
我没用脑子
It was her.
是她
She said she took it by mistake.
她说是她误拿了
- No, that's not true.- Oh, of course not.
- 不，那不是事实- 当然不是
Better count the spoons.
最好数数勺子
You were rightnot to want her here.
你不让她来是对的
I'd have expected more from John,though. Tuppy's his friend.
我对John期望挺高的，Tuppy可是他的朋友啊
She didn't take my fan.I left it on the...
她没拿我的扇子，我把它...
There's a telephone callfrom America.
有美国的电话
It's your father, Mr Windemere.
是你父亲，Windemere 先生
Not now.
现在不行
No, I'll take it.He'll worry.
我来接，他会担心的
- I love you.- I love you.
- 我爱你- 我爱你
And a woman brought this.
一个女人送来这个
She's waiting downstairs.
她在楼下等
Thank you.
谢谢
What are you doing here?We had an agreement.
你在这里干嘛?我们有协议
I came to return the fan.
我回来还扇子
How is your wifefeeling this morning?
你太太今早怎么样?
You don't get within ten feetof my wife.
你不许靠近我太太10尺
I only asked how she was.
我只是问候她
If you're here to tellher who you are...
如果你来这告诉她你是谁...
it's better coming from me.
还是我来吧
It's my secret, not yours.
是我的秘密，不是你的
You've kept it very well.
你保守的很好
Twenty years is a long time.
20年是个很久的时间
It doesn't seem to have beentoo much of a strain.
没造成什么伤害
You see a little girl...
你看个小女孩...
the right age,you push the thought aside.
合适的岁数把想法放在一边
Close the door.
关上门
Only at three o'clock,that in-between hour...
只在三点……
too late to do anything,too early for dinner...
干什么都晚了，吃饭有太早...
doors come flying open.
门大敞着
I don't believe you feelanything for her.
我不觉得你对她有感情
You care about yourself,and no-one else.
你只顾自己，没别人
Robert.
Your father needs to talk to you,he says it's important.
你父亲要跟你说话，很重要
Mrs Erlynnecame to return your fan.
Erlynne太太来还你扇子
She was just leaving.
她刚要走
No, don't leave, I need tospeak with you.
不，别走，我要跟你说话
- She'll miss her plane.- Just a few minutes.
- 她会耽误航班- 就一会儿
Your father's waiting on the phone.He said it's important.
你父亲在等你接电话，说是重要事
It would be a great mistake...
误航班...
to miss your plane.
会是个大错
I came to make sureyou got home safely.
我来确认你安全到家了
You can't leave yet.
你还不能走
You're my only witness thatnothing happened.
你是证明没事发生的唯一证人
Your witness?
你的证人?
I'm going to tell him the truth.
我要告诉他真相
What you did is your mistake.
你做错了
Your sack of bricks. You carry it.
你的麻烦，你来扛吧
You don't confess and had it offto someone who loves you.
你不能忏悔后把痛苦留给爱你的人
But everybody thinksyou were having...
但所有人都觉得你...
They'll think it anyway.It doesn't matter.
他们反正要那么想，没关系
That's not true,it matters to Tuppy.
那不是真相，对Tuppy来说有关系
I can't be responsiblefor ruining that.
我无法对毁了你们的婚约熟视无睹
You wanna spoil the onegood thing I've ever done?
你想把我做过的唯一善举给毁了吗?
It's only right to tell himthe truth.
告诉他真相是对的
You love each other!That's your truth.
你们相爱，这就是事实
Why you giving up your chanceof marriage to save mine?
你干嘛放弃一段好婚姻而拯救我?
- It doesn't make any sense.- I'll tell you the truth.
- 没道理- 我告诉你真相
But first, promise you're notgoing to make...
但首先答应我...
some grand confession.
不会去做大忏悔
Swear it on whatever youhold sacred.
以圣名起誓
I swear on my mother.
我以我母亲起誓
Pardon?
什么?
She's my guardian angel.
她是我的守护天使
My whole life, I've wantedto be like her.
我的一生，都想象她那样
I'm sure she wouldn't hold youto such a standard.
我确信她不想你以她为标准
She'd be so ashamed of me now.
她此时一定以我为耻
We all straddle the abyss,Mrs Windemere.
我们都在深渊挣扎，Windemere太太
If we never look down, how canwe know who we are?
如果我们不下望又怎能知道自己的真相?
A mother could never be ashamedof a daughter who didn't fall in.
母亲永远也不会因不堕落的女儿为耻
I hope you're right.
我希望你对
I've never been more certainof anything.
我从未如此确信过
I swear, them.
我发誓
What is it you wanted to tell me?
你要告诉我什么?
Nothing.
没事
I'll miss my plane.
我要耽误航班了
Goodbye, Mrs Windemere.
再见， Windemere太太
I hope we meet again.
我希望我们再见
So do I.
我也是
Mrs Erlynne.
Erlynne太太
- You didn't tell her?- No.
- 你没告诉她吧?- 没有
Why not?
为什么?
She has a mother.
她有母亲
A photograph in a locket.
小盒里的照片
It's a fairy tale.
那是个神话
A kind, caring mother, who lovesand watches over her.
一个善良、温存的妈妈，爱她，照顾她
I'm not going to take that away.
我不能把那个带走
And neither should you.
你也不该
Mrs Erlynne,One thousand Dollars.
Erlynne太太,1000美元
For one night I thought you were inlove with another woman.
有一晚，我觉得你爱上了其他女人
For one night I thought you were inlove with another man.
有一晚我以为你爱上了其他男人
- She was right.- Who?
- 她是对的- 谁?
Mrs Erlynne said we can'tshut our eyes...
Erlynne太太说我们不该对...
to everything that isn't perfect...
不完美熟视无睹...
otherwise we might fallinto a huge abyss.
否则我们会坠入深渊
We almost fell.
我们差一点
She's a smart woman.
她是个聪明的女人
She's a good woman.
她是个好女人
Better than I thought.
比我想的好
She insisted.
她很坚持
Who?
谁?
Meg.Something to remember her by.
Meg，一个对她的念想
And she explained everything.
而且她解释了一切
Everything?
一切?
Oh, yes, couse.The flat tyre, the dog.
哦，对，当然瘪轮胎，狗
The Brazilian taxi diver with thepregnant daughter...
巴西出租车司机和怀孕的女儿……
who lost her purse.
丢了钱包
And the only thing I can sayin my defense is...
而我的辩解是...
that I have no defense.
我没什么可辩解的
I jumped to conclusions andthought the worst.
我跳到结论，直接往最坏想
Where's this old crate going to?
这破筐往哪去?
I don't know.
我不知道
Will you marry me when get there?
到地方后你会嫁给我吗?
A man gets the wife he deserves.
男人娶该娶的女人为妻
Well, I've been a very, very bad man.
而我，可是一个很坏很坏的男人
You know, John,love's a battleground.
你知道，John,爱是战场
It was only a flesh wound.
而那只是皮肉之伤
Men advance,women resist.
男人预支，女人隐忍
We retreat and theyblock our escape.
我们退缩他们就堵住我们的退路
We can't win.
我们不能赢的
The sexes will never understandeach other.
两性无法彼此理解
Only because they take such painsto deceive each other.
他们以伤彼此伤害
Oh, hello Dumby,are you awake?
哦，Dumby,你醒着吗?
Am I winning?
我赢了吗?